All right.
好的。
Welcome back, everyone.
欢迎大家回来。
This is the session on posters and demos.
这是海报和演示环节。
We have seven talks in this session.
这个环节我们有七场讲座。
Each presenter will have about three minutes to present and afterwards,
每位演讲者将有大约三分钟的时间进行演讲，之后，
we'll have the actual posters and demo session in different BlueJeans rooms.
我们将在不同的BlueJeans房间进行实际的海报和演示会议。
The first presentation is by Junxiao Shi on
第一场演讲是由时俊霄进行的
NDNts Named Data Networking libraries for the Modern Web.
NDNts 命名数据网络库，适用于现代网络。
And Junxiao is currently at NIST he got his PhD from
Junxiao 目前在 NIST 工作，他的博士学位来自于
University of Arizona and currently a researcher at NIST.
Junxiao 目前在 NIST 工作，他的博士学位来自于亚利桑那大学，目前是 NIST 的一名研究员。他是核心的 NDN 开发者，并且一直在开发 NDN 网络转发器。
He's a core NDN developer and has been developing NDN network forwarders.
他是核心的 NDN 开发者，并且一直在开发 NDN 网络转发器。
Most recently the NBN dpdk forwarder.
最近他在开发 NBN dpdk 转发器。
Junxiao go ahead.
继继续吧。
>> Next page.
>> 下一页。
Hi, my Junxiao Shi.
你好，我是石俊霄。
Today I'm presenting my personal project NDNts: NDN Libraries for the Modern Web.
今天我将介绍我的个人项目NDNts：适用于现代网络的NDN库。
Next page.
~!@#$%^&*()
NDNts is a set of modern Java script libraries.
NDNts是一套现代的JavaScript库集。
It is compatible with both TypeScript and the JavaScript projects.
它同时兼容TypeScript和JavaScript项目。
It works in both Node.js and the browser environment and
它可以同时在Node.js和浏览器环境中运行，
we have good test coverage as well as automated and manual browser test.
我们拥有良好的测试覆盖率，以及自动化和手动的浏览器测试。
NDNts libraries can operate a stand alone without using a a forwarder or
NDNts库可以独立运行，无需使用转发器或
if you chose, it can connect to NFD or NDN- DPDK forwarders.
如果您选择，它可以连接到NFD或NDN-DPDK转发器。
Most importantly, NDNts project is active maintains new features are being
最重要的是，NDNts项目正在积极维护，新功能正在不断推出。
added mostly to the libraries and we support the latest NDN specifications.
添加到库中的内容大多数都是最新的，我们支持最新的NDN规范。
Next page.
下一页。
During the support poster demo session,
在支持海报演示会议期间，
I will show some code samples of the endpoint API.
我将展示一些端点API的代码示例。
This is a new API design which is a better version of the face.
这是一个新的API设计，它是面部识别的一个更好的版本。
And on the left side, there is the features of the current face.
在左侧是当前面部的特征。
It has only a little bit of fisher, but with endpoint it will automatic handle
它只有一点点的渔夫特性，但是配合端点，它将会自动处理。
a few things such as the automatic interest retransmission, date signing and
自动兴趣重传、日期签名等几项功能，
verification based on trust schemas.
基于信任模式的验证。
Data buffering on the producer side, and
生产者端的数据缓冲，以及
it also automatically handles the transport errors.
它还会自动处理传输错误。
So that in the application you just need to focus on application logic.
所以在应用程序中，你只需要专注于应用逻辑。
Next page.
下一页。
In the demo session, I will also show some code samples of
在演示环节中，我还会展示一些代码示例。
Trust Schema implementation.
信任模式实现。
So, Trust Schema is this implementation
所以，信任模式就是这种实现。
is inspired by Casey's talk last year
受到了Casey去年演讲的启发
of Versatile Security Toolkit.
受到了Casey去年演讲的启发，多功能安全工具包。Next Page.
Next Page.
下一页。
I will show online web application which displaces
我将展示一个在线Web应用程序，它显示
NLSR status in today's global NDN testbed.
我将展示一个在线Web应用程序，它显示今天全球NDN测试床的NLSR状态。And there's a URL example on top right corner you can already try to look at it.
And there's a URL example on top right corner you can already try to look at it.
右上角有一个URL示例，你可以尝试去查看一下。
Next page.
下一页。
I will show my implementation of the NDN certificate Management Protocol.
我将展示我的NDN证书管理协议的实现。
This includes a Node.js web application called
这包括一个名为的Node.js网络应用程序
the NDNts Personal Certificate Authority, as well as a commander land client
NDNts个人证书颁发机构，以及一个指挥地客户端
of the NDNts certified management protocol to request a certificate.
请求证书的NDNts认证管理协议。
Next page.
请翻到下一页。
And finally, I will show a demo of the home civilians camera.
最后，我将展示一个家用民用摄像头的演示。
I demo the older version of this application two years ago,
两年前，我演示了这个应用程序的旧版本。
which was written on NDNts.
它是基于NDNts编写的。
But now I have rebuilt this application with my new libraries NDNts.
但现在我已经用我新的库NDNts重建了这个应用程序。
I also added a screencast feature and
我还添加了一个屏幕录制功能，并且
this will be online demo accessible using this UI.
这将是一个在线演示，可以通过这个用户界面访问。
Okay, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
That's all from me, I hope you can join me after the post session.
我就说到这里，希望你能在会后加入我。
>> Thank you very much Junxiao.
>> 非常感谢你，俊霄。
Next talk is by Alex Afanasyev.
下一场演讲将由Alex Afanasyev主持。
CertCoalesce: Effecient Certificate Pool for NDN-Based Systems.
CertCoalesce：基于NDN系统的高效证书池。
Alex is an assistant professor at Florida International University.
亚历克斯是佛罗里达国际大学的助理教授。
His main research focus is on next generation architectures as part of
他的主要研究重点是作为下一代架构的一部分
the NDN project, in particular scalability and
他的主要研究重点是作为下一代架构的一部分，NDN项目，特别是可扩展性和基于名称的路由，自动配置autoconfiguration，
name based routing, auto configuration autoconfiguration,
基于名称的路由，自动配置autoconfiguration，
distributed data synchronization as well as application and network security.
分布式数据同步以及应用程序和网络安全。
Alex?
~!@#$%^&*()
>> Sure, so you probably can skip the title slide of my presentation.
当然，所以你可能可以跳过我的演讲的标题幻灯片。
Just move.
继续前进。
Yeah.
是的。
So basically the motivation for
所以基本上动机是
this work is a simple assumption that we need the many certificates.
这项工作是一个简单的假设，我们需要许多证书。
And so for example, it needs to be used for to realize least privileges
例如，它需要被用来实现最小权限原则。
separation, for example, we have kind of very rich namespace,
分离，例如，我们有一种非常丰富的命名空间，
you want to have a separate key for individual pieces of that namespace,
您希望为该命名空间的各个部分拥有独立的键，
like foo/bar/a, foo/bar/b and so forth, and so on.
像foo/bar/a、foo/bar/b等等。
Another part is basically trying to limit exposure of individual keys.
另一部分基本上是试图限制单个密钥的暴露。
So for example, if you kinda have a validity of one year,
例如，如果证书的有效期大约是一年，
then you have to implement some mechanism to revoke the certificate.
那么你必须实施一些机制来撤销证书。
If you have a validity period of a few minutes,
如果你的有效期只有几分钟，
then you probably don't need the additional mechanisms.
那么你可能不需要额外的机制。
And next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So the basic approach in traditional systems is to use kind of
因此，在传统系统中的基本方法是使用某种方式
ordinary certificate systems where on one side you generate the public key pair.
在普通的证书系统中，一方会生成公钥对。
And whenever you want to get a certificate you basically request certificate
当你想要获取证书时，你基本上是在请求证书。
for this pair.
对于这对。
I mean in theory, you can go certificate authority or
理论上来说，你可以去找证书颁发机构或者
certificate issuer can reissue certificates for the same public key.
证书颁发机构可以为相同的公钥重新颁发证书。
But that's not a great idea because you want to limit exposure of individual keys.
但这并不是一个好主意，因为你想要限制单个密钥的暴露风险。
That's kind of a basic principle.
这是一条基本原则。
And the limitation or kind of the outcome, if you want to have tons of certificates
以及限制或者某种成果的种类，如果你想拥有大量的证书
for different namespace or tons of certificates for kind of different
对于不同的命名空间或者大量不同种类的证书，
time granularities, it's both the network overhead and storage requirement.
对于不同的时间粒度来说，它既关系到网络开销也关系到存储需求。
And basically what I'm trying to do as part of this work is trying to do some
我在这项工作中基本上尝试做的是尝试进行一些
optimization maybe with a few trade-offs, but trying to do some optimization.
在这项工作中，我基本上尝试做的是尝试进行一些优化，可能会有一些权衡，但还是试图进行一些优化。下一张幻灯片。
So the next slide.
所以下一张幻灯片。
So the basic process here, is still based on elliptic curve cryptography,
所以基本过程仍然是基于椭圆曲线密码学的，
but instead of having a single key or single private public key, and
但是，与其拥有一把单独的密钥或一对单一的私钥和公钥，
then getting the single certificate, you're basically creating a master key or
那么，获取单一证书，你基本上是在创建一个主密钥或者
caterpillar key that can bootstrap a sequence of infinite sequence of
毛毛虫密钥可以引导一个无限序列的序列。
contracts actual public, private key pairs that you can use in the future.
合同实际上是可以在将来使用的公钥、私钥对。
You can request certification of that the single key which will result in
您可以请求对那个将产生的单一密钥进行认证，以便在未来使用。
on a kind of certificate the isher site, generation of unlimited
在某种证书发行网站上，生成无限的~!@#$%^&*()
sequence of keys, unlimited sequence of public keys and
私钥序列、无限的公钥序列以及
correspondingly it can generate unlimited sequence of certificates basically.
相应地，它基本上可以生成无限序列的证书。
And in case of IT devices, this can be quite easy.
在信息技术设备的情况下，这可以相当简单。
You can just store a single, this master key, on the device.
你可以只在设备上存储一个这样的主密钥。
And whenever you need it, you just kind of using the basic conventions,
而且每当你需要的时候，你只需遵循基本的约定，
naming conventions.
命名约定。
You do define when To use specific key, quickly you generate that private key.
您确实定义了何时使用特定密钥，您会迅速生成那个私钥。
As soon as on the certificates on authority site,
您一旦在权威网站上的证书上，
this key is the corresponding certificate that have been created.
这个密钥是已经创建的相应证书。
I'll probably stop here unless I have a few more minutes.
我可能会在这里停下来，除非我还有几分钟的时间。
But in any case this is preliminary work,
但无论如何这都是初步工作，
we can have devise some ideas how this can be done.
我们可以想出一些方法来实现这个目标。
We kind of borrowed some ideas from some of the vehicular work
我们有点借鉴了一些车辆工作方面的想法。
that have been proposed recently.
最近提出的那些建议。
I would not use an everything from that environment, but
我不会使用那个环境中的所有东西，但是
mostly focusing on the ability to have a single key.
大多数集中在拥有单一密钥的能力上。
Generating, creating multitude of kind of derivative keys even though
即便是生成、创建了许多种衍生密钥，仍然保留了在此衍生过程中的前向保密属性。
And ability to independent generate on the certificate issuer site
以及在证书颁发方的网站上独立生成的能力。
certificates if your whatever original master key is still not revoked.
证书如果你的任何原始主密钥仍未被吊销。
So basically some kind of combination mechanism of certificate authority or
所以基本上是某种结合了证书颁发机构或者
issuing a certificate and revocation certificates by the way of
发放证书和通过某种方式撤销证书
not issuing new certificates okay, I guess that would be.
不再发放新证书，我想这应该是可以的。
>> Okay thank you, Alex.
好的，谢谢你，亚历克斯。
Our next presenter is Sanjeev Ramani on MDN Viber vibration assistant
我们的下一位演讲者是Sanjeev Ramani，他将介绍MDN Viber振动助手。
automated bootstrapping of IoT devices.
自动引导物联网设备。
Sanjeev is a PHD student At [COUGH] Florida International University working
Sanjeev 是一名在佛罗里达国际大学攻读博士学位的学生，他正在工作。
with Alex under the supervision of Alex.
在 Alex 的指导下工作。
His research interests include NDNViber security as well as privacy and
他的研究兴趣包括NDNViber的安全性以及隐私保护和
trust management in wireless sensor networks and IOT devices.
他的研究兴趣包括无线传感器网络和物联网设备中的信任管理。
Sanjeev, >> Hope I'm visible and
Sanjeev，>> 希望我是可见的并且
all of you can hear me out.
你们都能听到我说话。
Thank you, Lotti.
谢谢你，洛蒂。
Can you go to the next slide, well all of us.
能不能翻到下一张幻灯片，我们大家。
Yeah, so all of us know that IoT devices have
是的，所以我们都知道物联网设备已经
pretty much penetrated into everyone's daily livelihood.
已经在很大程度上渗透进了每个人的日常生活中。
And we have a lot of wearable devices and
已经有很多可穿戴设备和其他种类的物联网设备，我们每天都在使用。
other kinds of IoT devices that we use on a day to day basis.
我们日常使用的其他种类的物联网设备。
But, and in the near future, we assume it's going to explode to a larger extent.
但是，在不久的将来，我们预计它将会有更大规模的爆炸性增长。
An important aspect in any IoT devices life cycle is the bootstrapping process
物联网设备生命周期中的一个重要方面是引导过程。
rather than it gets to know of the network or environment it will be working in.
而它实际上会了解它将要工作的网络或环境。
And the network on the other hand actually gets to know
而另一方面，网络实际上也会了解
about the device that's joining the environment and so,
关于即将加入环境的设备，因此，
that they can have trustworthy communication and exchanges later on.
因此，他们之后能够进行可信赖的沟通和交流。
So, usually this bootstrapping happens in an auxiliary channel or
因此，通常这种引导过程发生在一个辅助通道中或者
an out of band channel, and when the bootstrapping keys and
在一个辅助通道中，当引导密钥和其他信息加密材料被交换时。
other info crypto material are exchanged.
其他信息加密材料被交换。
So, in our exploration, we basically surveyed all the out of band
所以，在我们的探索中，我们基本上调查了所有的带外
channels to identify, which would be most apt in a situation
所以，在我们的探索中，我们基本上调查了所有的带外频道，以确定哪个在特定情况下最合适，而不是你有一个物联网设备却不在视线范围内。
rather than you have an IoT device that's not in the line of sight.
相反，你有一个物联网设备却不在视线范围内。
It's probably behind the wall or embedded on the table.
它可能在墙后面或嵌在桌子里。
And we want to try to bootstrap this device.
我们希望尝试引导启动这个设备。
By not trying to increase the complexity of the hardware that is associated with
我们并不试图增加与此相关的硬件的复杂性。
the device, but just trying to use a simple accelerometer or
我们只是尝试使用一个简单的加速度计或
a device or a sensor that's pretty
一个相当普遍的设备或传感器，它在如今大多数物联网设备中都有所应用。
much available with most of the IoT devices that come in today.
在如今的大多数物联网设备中都广泛应用。
So that's when we place our hands on vibration based autobank
所以那时我们就把手放在基于振动的自动银行设备上。
channel which basically give us multiple security benefits as
通道基本上为我们提供了多重安全保障。
well which basically starts our proximity based trust.
这基本上是我们基于接近性的信任的起点。
Because you need to have the device and the controller at pretty close
因为你需要将设备和控制器放得非常近
quarters in close less than in a distance of less than 1.5 centimeters for
距离小于1.5厘米的范围内以便于
the vibrations to be actually felt by the IoT device and bootstrap.
以便于物联网设备实际感受到振动并进行引导启动。
And also the NDNViber design that we came up with using
以及我们提出的使用NDNViber设计，
this vibration based channel.
这种基于振动的通道。
Can be a dynamic approach as against the most traditional static
可以是一种与最传统的静态方式相对的动态方法
ways of doing bootstrapping.
引导启动的方法。
And also we can use commodity or stock Android phones as controllers.
我们还可以使用普通或原生安卓手机作为控制器。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So, the NDNViber overview, I'll probably just run through this pretty quick.
那么，NDNViber概述，我可能会很快地简单跑一遍。
It's split into four different stages starting with the pilot sequence which
它分为四个不同的阶段，从引导序列开始，该序列会……
would basically awaken the IoT device and make it listen on the vibration channel
将基本唤醒物联网设备，并使其在振动通道上进行监听。
for any triggers or any information that's passed on by the controller.
用于接收任何由控制器传递的触发器或任何信息。
Then the trigger sequence follows wherein,
然后是触发器序列的执行，其中，
there is an exchange of environment information, and
接着是环境信息的交换，以及
also learning information like temporary cryptographic keys or encryption keys.
接着是学习信息，如临时加密密钥或者加密密钥。
And even the channel that the device should use in further
以及设备在之后应使用的频道
communication when in the network.
通信时在网络中。
Following the trigger sequence and is the anchor of exchanges where the device after
在触发序列之后，是设备之后交换的锚点。
the completion of the anchor sequence gets to know of the trust anchor certificate.
锚点序列完成后，将了解信任锚证书。
And finally we have the NDN cert sequence that runs when the device is
在设备运行时，最后我们有NDN证书序列。
able to generate its and obtain its Indian certificate for the key namespace and
能够为关键的命名空间生成并获取其NDN证书，
use it for signing information that it produces in the network.
将其用于对网络中产生的信息进行签名。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So basically this is the overview and
所以基本上这就是概览，
if you can join me at the poster we could discuss further about.
如果你能和我一起来到海报前，我们可以进一步讨论。
What does a specific in coding scheme that we used for
特定的编码方案我们使用了什么~!@#$%^&*()
vibration channel and how it's used in NDNViber.
振动通道以及它在NDNViber中的使用方式。
And what are the advantages that we see in terms of bootstrapping
我们在引导方面看到的优势有哪些？
multiple devices at the same time, the security properties that we observed and
同时使用多个设备时，我们观察到的安全属性以及
also the challenges in evaluation, preliminary evaluation that we have.
我们所面临的评估挑战，以及我们所进行的初步评估。
That's pretty much it for this I guess I continue next again.
这大概就是这个的全部了，我想我接下来会继续进行。
>> Yes so you have two posters.
是的，所以你有两张海报。
This is the second one on use to secure smartphone distribution.
这是第二个用于确保智能手机分发的海报。
>> Okay, so this is basically in its preliminary exploration stage.
好的，所以这基本上还处于初步探索阶段。
This is more of we all know that smart grids is a modern adoption
这更多的是我们都知道智能电网是一种现代化的采纳。
of power systems with the potential to revolutionize power distribution and
的电力系统，具有彻底改变电力分配和管理的潜力。
management.
管理。
In a general setting you have multiple,
在一般情况下，你会有多个，
multiple stakeholders be the consumer, the producer of power.
在一般情况下，你会有多个利益相关者，无论是消费者还是电力生产者。
And a lot of other intermediary devices, be it sensor or
和许多其他中间设备，无论是传感器还是
any transmission, right, the transformers that
变压器，对，那些变压器可以转换电力，无论是升压还是降压变压器。
transform the electricity from step-up, step-down transformers.
将电力从升压变压器或降压变压器转换过来。
There are a lot of devices and the digital communication that happens among these
这些设备之间发生了大量的数字通信。
devices is basically the support system for the whole operation of the smart grid.
设备基本上是智能电网整个运作的支持系统。
And also smart grid basically provides us decouple the wrong
与此同时，智能电网基本上为我们提供了解耦错误的功能。
interconnection that power generation sites have with the consumption sites and
电力发电站与消费地点之间的互联互通，
makes power basically a commodity that can be requested for.
使电力基本上成为了一种可以请求的商品。
Well so I have mentioned two types of information that's basically exchanged in
好的，所以我提到了两种基本上在这个系统中交换的信息。
this system that's more a technical data corresponding to the energy profiles.
这个系统主要涉及与能源特性相对应的技术数据。
And management related information that's building, pricing,
以及与建筑、定价相关的管理信息，
and even information that can be used for analytics to identify how
以及甚至可以用于分析以识别如何
new infrastructure has to be established and other things.
新的基础设施需要建立以及其他事项。
And in the end, we believe with all the inherent features,
最终，我们相信凭借所有这些内在特性，
like data centric security Optimal routing and other
像数据中心安全、最优路由等其他
benefits of the data centric approach, data centric
数据中心方法的好处，数据中心
architecture can provide a better is a good fit for smart grid communication.
架构可以更好地适用于智能电网通信。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
Yeah, so the common issues that we see with the current SmartGrid set up is that
是的，我们在当前智能电网设置中看到的常见问题是
most of these power systems are usually legacy systems.
大多数这些电力系统通常是传统系统。
And they're not interface relative to each other.
它们之间并没有相互关联的界面。
So If you're talking about an IoT device as the end consumer and
因此，如果你谈论的是作为最终消费者的物联网设备与
the power generation sites being having large machinary probably the interface
因此，如果你谈论的是作为最终消费者的物联网设备与大型机械设备可能存在的接口问题，当前系统中这些设备之间的交互并没有得到很好的处理。
between these devices is not very well taken care of in the current system.
在当前系统中，这些设备之间的交互并没有得到很好的处理。
And also there are a lot of security concerns with information power flowing
在当前系统中，这些设备之间的交互并没有得到很好的处理。并且，信息流动也存在许多安全问题，这些信息通过不同的渠道和媒介传播，而且需要进行双重检查。
With NDN What we can do is more of an off by default approach wherein only
在使用NDN的情况下，我们可以采取一种默认关闭的方法，仅在必要时才开启。
when any of the nodes are required or requested for
当任何节点需要或被请求时
information they could be turned on and hence, you can prevent any bad
信息可以被启用，因此，你可以防止任何不良情况发生。
information coming in or any leaks that can happen in the system.
信息的传入或系统中可能发生的任何泄露。
Next slide.
下一张幻灯片。
I probably have a small example here.
我这里可能有一个小例子。
Let's consider a smart home.
让我们考虑一下智能家居。
I hope I'm not running out of time on it.
我希望我没有在这件事上耗尽时间。
I'll make it real quick.
我会很快做完的。
So a smart home with the smart refrigerator that's
如此智能的家庭拥有的那个智能冰箱就是...
trying to request for power.
试图请求供电。
It basically has, like I told you there are different stakeholders different
它基本上就像我告诉你的，有不同的利益相关者不同的
notes are different people involved in this whole entire communication and
笔记涉及到这整个沟通过程中的不同人员。
NDN provides with its flexible naming convention and
NDN通过其灵活的命名规则和
other benefits makes it an easier option to achieve this power which is
通过其它好处使得它成为实现这种能力的一个更容易的选择，这种能力是
basically decoupled as a commodity by the smart credit system and
通过智能信用系统将其基本上作为一种商品进行了解耦，并且
request efficiently and use it.
通过智能信用系统将其基本上作为一种商品进行了解耦，并且高效地请求并使用它。下一张幻灯片，所以当你路过或
Next slide, so when you pass by or
下一张幻灯片，所以当你路过或
when we are at the poster session probably we can
当我们在海报展示环节，我们或许可以
discuss on how NDN basically helps in all these smart-grid operations and
讨论NDN如何在所有这些智能电网操作中发挥基础作用，以及通过采用NDN，智能电网运行可以变得更加顺畅。
the smart grid operation can be made more hassle free with the adoption of NDN.
通过采用NDN，智能电网运行可以变得更加顺畅。
Thank you, I guess.
谢谢，我想是的。
>> All right.
>> 好的。
Thank you, Sanjeev.
谢谢你，Sanjeev。
Next speaker is Italo Brito
下一位发言者是Italo Brito。
on the topic of Distance Vector Routing for NDN.
关于NDN的距离向量路由的话题。
Italo is a PhD student at Federal University of Bahia in Brazil.
Italo 是巴西巴伊亚联邦大学的一名博士研究生。
Go ahead Italo.
继续吧，Italo。
>> Hello, everyone.
>> 大家好。
Good afternoon?
下午好？
So this work is a collaboration between myself, my advisor,
所以这项工作是我和我的导师合作的，
Professor Lambino, and also Professor Alicia Zang from UCLA.
兰比诺教授，以及来自加州大学洛杉矶分校的阿丽西亚·张教授。
So the idea is to propose a distance vector routing algorithm for the engine.
因此，这个想法是为引擎提出一个距离向量路由算法。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So, the NDN in the mobile Adhoc Scenarios presents some challenges.
因此，在移动Adhoc场景中的NDN呈现了一些挑战。
And the queue has deployed engine routing protocol NLSR is
因此，队列中部署了基于链路状态算法的引擎路由协议NLSR。
based on link state algorithms.
基于链路状态算法。
Link state ours require synchronization between the link state database across
链路状态数据库需要在各个节点之间进行同步。
the nodes, anything and in the mobile doc scenarios,
节点、任何事物以及在移动文档场景中，
which is our wireless, dynamic environments, they design a lightweight
它们设计了一种轻量级的无线动态环境，
routing protocol, to propagate the rapidly change data reachability information.
路由协议用于传播快速变化的数据可达性信息。
The distance vector routing protocol enables each node to selectively
距离矢量路由协议使得每个节点能够有选择地
the action exchange, name prefix, reachability information and also to
动作交换、名称前缀、可达性信息以及也能够
estimate the wish ability to design data in a distributed in a synchronous manner
估计愿望能力在分布式同步方式中设计数据。
different from the link state our which require the synchronization the distance
与链路状态路由不同，它需要同步距离。
vector is based on distribution and a synchronous communication.
矢量是基于分布式的和同步通信的。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So our goal is to propose a simplest as possible way to propagate the name
因此，我们的目标是提出一种尽可能简单的方式来传播名称。
prefix reachability information in a mobile adhoc scenario, and
在移动自组织网络场景中的前缀可达性信息，以及
our designs base it on dynamically detect the neighbors.
我们的设计基于动态检测邻居节点。
Upon detecting a neighbor,
在检测到邻居节点后，
the node sends an interest to retrieve the neighbor's distance vector information,
节点发送一个兴趣请求以检索邻居的距离向量信息，
the routes and we need to remember that the interest they are not secured but
我们需要记住，这些路由的兴趣请求并没有被加密，但是
in our case is not a problem because it's just a request and then neighbors replies
在我们的情况下这不是问题，因为这只是一个请求，然后邻居会回复。
back with the reachability information which is the distance vector the house.
回传的是可达性信息，即到房子的距离向量。
And the data packets are secured and can be validated.
数据包是安全的，可以进行验证。
So we can make sure that the data is valid.
所以我们可以确保数据是有效的。
We use the distributed Bellman-Ford algorithm with sequence number approach.
我们使用带序列号方法的分布式贝尔曼-福特算法。
Those are true,
这些是真的，
well-known algorithm from the mobile adhoc network research community.
来自移动自组织网络研究社区的众所周知的算法。
So we just took advantage of the same well-known algorithms.
所以我们只是利用了同样众所周知的算法。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
Our naming schema, we are based mainly on two message,
我们的命名方案主要基于两种消息，
the hello message, which is the one that is used for Neighbor discover and
邻居发现使用的hello消息，它是用于发现邻居的消息，
also it is an extended hello message because it It is also used to inform
它也是一种扩展的hello消息，因为它还被用来通知
the neighbors about a new D vector information on the node.
它也是一种扩展的hello消息，因为它还被用来通知邻居们关于节点上的新D向量信息。So, we are going to discuss this a little bit later on the poster session.
So, we are going to discuss this a little bit later on the poster session.
所以，我们稍后会在海报展示环节讨论这个问题。
But the other type of message is the distance vector information.
但另一种类型的信息是距离矢量信息。
Then we use this naming schema.
然后我们使用这种命名方案。
We have the ndvr, dvinfo, and also the halter name and
我们有ndvr、dvinfo，还有halter name和~!@#$%^&*()
the version of the package, the version of the interest of the data.
包的版本，数据兴趣的版本。
And those messages are silent by the routers key.
而这些信息通过路由器密钥被静默处理。
And we also have the key exchange we use pretty much the same rock
而我们在进行密钥交换时，基本上也是使用相同的方法。
the same naming schema, as analysts use to the nodes that they exchange the key.
使用与分析师交换密钥时相同的命名模式。
The certificate key to validate the data,
用于验证数据的证书密钥，
our assumption is that each node must know about a trust anchor.
我们的假设是每个节点都必须了解一个信任锚点。
In this case, the certificate for the slash network name.
在这种情况下，是针对斜杠网络名称的证书。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
In this example, we just have two wireless routers, router A and router B.
在这个例子中，我们只有两个无线路由器，路由器A和路由器B。
In this case UFBA is just the hotter the network name.
在这种情况下，UFBA 只是网络名称的热点。
It could be Google, it could be UCLA.
它可以是谷歌，也可以是加州大学洛杉矶分校。
It could be NIST, anything that you want, but it's just on a sample.
它可以是国家标准技术研究所（NIST），或者任何你想要的东西，但这只是一个样本。
And the first step is the hotter sent out interest on the network to say Hello,
第一步是通过网络发送兴趣信号来打招呼，表示友好。
this is hotter A and
~!@#$%^&*()
each URC sent the same interest in the network, in the wi-fi network.
每个URC在Wi-Fi网络中发送了相同的兴趣。
As soon as the hotter get to know about the existence of another hotter
一旦一个热点得知另一个热点的存在
this hotter start requesting the distance factory formation for
这个更热的开始请求距离工厂形成的信息
the hotter, which means we send our interest asking for
我们发送我们的兴趣请求，这意味着我们更加热切地想要
the information for the health that we just discovered.
我们刚刚发现的健康信息。
And as soon as the hotter process, the request,
它一旦接受到更热的处理请求，
it replies back with the distance vector information.
它会回复距离矢量信息。
So it's sending these vector data package back to the requester.
所以它会把这些矢量数据包发送回请求者。
Next slide please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So I think is this in, I hope you can join us on the poster section.
所以我认为这是在……我希望你能加入我们的海报部分。
In the poster section we will discuss a little bit more about
在海报部分，我们将会进一步讨论关于……
the prototype that we developed on ndnSIM 2.8.
我们在ndnSIM 2.8上开发的原型。
We are going to present some preliminary results from the evaluation that we use,
我们将展示一些我们使用的评估的初步结果，
using the random walk mobility model, and comparing with DTSN,
我们使用随机漫步移动模型，并与DTSN进行比较，
which is a data synchronization algorithm.
它是一种数据同步算法。
And you're gonna present some challenges some ongoing works about this test.
你将会呈现一些关于这个测试的挑战和正在进行的工作。
Thank you.
谢谢。
>> Okay, thank you, Lito.
好的，谢谢你，Lito。
Next presenter is Amar Abane
下一位演讲者是Amar Abane。
on managing MDN with the Multiverse Network Management System.
关于使用多元宇宙网络管理系统管理MDN。
Amar got his PhD from CNAM in France, and he's currently a researcher.
阿玛尔在法国国家应用科学院（CNAM）获得了博士学位，目前是一名研究员。
And he directs network technologies division at NIST.
他在美国国家标准与技术研究院（NIST）负责网络技术部门。
Go ahead, Amar.
请继续，阿马尔。
>> Okay, thanks.
>> 好的，谢谢。
Yeah, so this is the Multiverse Network Management System Project.
是的，这就是多元宇宙网络管理系统项目。
So just as a situation to describe the situation.
所以这只是一个用来描述情况的情景。
So when we deal with the NDN deployments,
所以当我们处理NDN部署时，
some management features are required or at least some configurations
因此，当我们处理NDN部署时，一些管理功能是必需的，或者至少需要一些配置。
are needed on the forwarders like, basically routing information.
需要在转发器上配置基本的路由信息。
But at least so, to manage our NDN network,
但至少如此，为了管理我们的NDN网络，
we have some different situations.
我们面临着一些不同的情况。
So we can manage the NDN network via an IP network.
所以我们可以通过IP网络来管理NDN网络。
If we for example, if we need the remote management, we can do it.
如果我们需要远程管理，我们可以做到这一点。
Can also manage the NDN network over both IP and NDN and
还可以通过IP和NDN来管理NDN网络。
since there are still some IP, some equipment that are using IP.
由于仍然有一些设备在使用IP，所以我们也需要管理一部分基于IP的网络。
But we also need to manage some parts of
由于仍然有一些设备在使用IP，所以我们也需要管理一部分
the IP network or so to NDN or IP.
IP网络或者是到NDN或者是IP。
And we think it may be useful to have one management solution for
我们认为可能有必要为这些不同情况或不同宇宙提供一个统一的管理解决方案。
these different situations or different universes.
这些不同情况或不同宇宙。
So, next slide, please.
那么，请换到下一张幻灯片。
Yes, so that's what the multiverse network management system is designed for.
是的，这正是多元宇宙网络管理系统设计的目的。
So we aim to manage these different situations.
所以我们的目标是管理这些不同的情况。
Next slide.
下一张幻灯片。
Yeah, so briefly it's a centralized management and
是的，简而言之，它是一种集中管理方式。
we want to stick with this very simple architecture and very familiar.
我们希望坚持使用这种非常简单且非常熟悉的架构。
So we have the Data plane with
我们有数据平面与
the NDN-DPDK forwarders which we are working to support currently.
我们目前正在努力支持的NDN-DPDK转发器。
And they are for the Control plane they are agent deployed on each node and
我们目前正在努力支持的NDN-DPDK转发器。它们是控制平面的组成部分，它们是部署在每个节点上的代理，they are agents are connected to the controller.
they are agents are connected to the controller.
它们是连接到控制器的代理。
And there is a controller provides some centralized management features there
而且那里有一个控制器提供了一些集中管理功能。
are some of them are automatic features like face creation, face computation.
其中一些是自动功能，如人脸创建、人脸计算。
And some other things are provided to the operator to be used manually.
还有一些其他东西是提供给操作员手动使用的。
And there is also, in addition to the management, there is an telemetry
还有除了管理之外，还有遥测功能。
feature integrated with these agents, depending on what
这些代理集成的功能，取决于什么
measurements are implemented on the agent.
代理上实施了测量。
Yeah, so in the poster,
嗯，所以在海报中，
there will be basically some screenshots of what's implemented so far and
所以海报中基本上会有一些到目前为止实现的功能的截图，
some design course also that's in this project.
这个项目中也包含了一些设计课程。
>> I think that's it.
>> 我想就这样了。
Yeah, thanks.
嗯，谢谢。
>> Okay, thank you Amar.
好的，谢谢Amar。
Next speaker is Quassim Karrakchuo on Novel P4 Target Architecture for
下一位演讲者是Quassim Karrakchuo，主题是“新型P4目标架构”。
Runtime-Reconfigurable NDN Data Planes.
运行时可重配置的NDN数据平面。
Quassim received his Bachelor's Degree from France and
Quassim 从法国获得了他的学士学位，并且
he's currently a PhD student at University of Ottawa.
他目前是渥太华大学的博士研究生。
With research interests that include ICN, SDN and Cloud Technologies.
他的研究兴趣包括信息中心网络（ICN）、软件定义网络（SDN）和云技术。
Go ahead Ouassim.
继续吧，Ouassim。
>> Thank you Lotfi.
>> 谢谢你，Lotfi。
Hello, everyone.
大家好。
So today I give you a quick introduction of our work that is titled,
所以今天我将快速介绍我们的工作，其标题为，
a Novelty P4 Targets Architecture for Runtime Reconfigurable Engine Data Planes.
一种针对运行时可重配置引擎数据平面的新颖P4目标架构。下一张幻灯片，请。
Next slide, please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So the motivation of our work is that in the current switches,
所以我们工作的动机是，在当前的交换机中，
the switch functionalities are usually fixed, and
交换机的功能通常是固定的，而且
can only be changed by the switch manufacturer.
通常只能由交换机制造商来更改。
That means that the algorithms that processed the packets inside the switch,
这意味着在交换机内部处理数据包的算法，通常只能由交换机制造商来更改，它们要么像硬件一样经过优化，要么直接在硬件中硬编码。
there are either like hardware optimized and hard coded in the hardware.
它们要么像硬件一样经过优化，要么直接在硬件中硬编码。
So they can only be changed by buying the new hardware, or they are part of
所以它们只能通过购买新硬件来更改，或者它们是一部分
the firmware of the switch, though if a new protocol needs to be supported.
因此，如果需要支持新的协议，网络操作员将不得不等待交换机制造商的新更新。
The network operator will have to wait for a new update from the switch manufacturer.
因此，网络操作员将不得不等待交换机制造商的新更新。
So, P4 was introduced to solve this limitation by
因此，为了解决这一限制，P4语言被引入。
opening up the data plane and allowing the network operators to
打开数据平面并允许网络运营商自定义编写交换机中的行为。
specify themselves their own custom for writing behaviors in their switches.
指定他们自己的自定义来编写他们交换机中的行为。
So how does it work?
那么它是如何工作的呢？
The network operators will use P4 which is a high level programming
网络运营商将使用P4，这是一种高级编程
language to program their data planes using the P4
语言来编程他们的数据平面使用P4。
programs in order to completely specify everything they need in their switches.
为了完全指定他们在交换机中需要的一切，他们需要编写程序。
Now, the current P4 architectures, they
现在，当前的P4架构，它们
have a small limitation which is that
它们有一个小限制，即
usually one switch can only run one big P4 program at a time.
通常一个交换机一次只能运行一个大型P4程序。
So that means that if a network operator wants to add a new functionality to
那就意味着如果网络运营商想要向他们的交换机添加新功能，他们必须编辑这个大型P4程序。
their switch, they have to edit this large P4 program.
that means if network operators want to add new features to their switch, they have to edit this large P4 program.
And then upload it in the switch, which needs to be reset,
然后将其上传到需要重置的交换机中，
to update the whole program that's processes everything in the switch.
然后更新交换机中处理所有事务的整个程序。
So there is always a downtime that is needed
因此总是需要一段停机时间。
each time you do an update to add the functionality to a switch.
每次更新都是为了给交换机增加功能。
And a second limitation of P4, which is more specific to the case of NDN
P4的第二个限制更具体地针对了NDN的情况。
is that P4 was actually designed in the context of the IP world.
P4实际上是在IP世界的背景下设计的。
Where the headers are usually fixed and have fields that have a fixed size, right?
在这种情况下，报头通常是固定的，并且具有固定大小的字段，对吗？
And so, when you want to apply it directly to NDN, where one of the main fields
在这种情况下，当你想要将其直接应用于NDN时，其中一个主要字段
in the headers is the constants name, which is a string of a variable length.
在头部中是常量名，它是一个变长的字符串。
There are some limitations that you have to overcome.
您需要克服一些限制。
Okay, the next slide please.
好的，请换到下一张幻灯片。
So, the main objective of our work is to have an engine
那么，我们工作的主要目标是拥有一个引擎，
data plane that has some other programmability using P4.
我们的工作主要目标是拥有一个数据平面，它能够使用P4进行其他一些程序化操作。
And we want to do it in a way where you can assign a specific custom writing
我们希望以一种方式来实现，你可以指派一个特定的自定义写入操作。
logic to a specific namespace that is all encompassed in the P4 function.
将逻辑指派给一个特定的命名空间，这全部包含在P4函数中。
So your associates a custom P4 function, going and then space.
将自定义的P4函数关联到一个命名空间中去。
And we want to do it in a way where all these P4 functions are independent.
我们希望以一种方式来实现，所有这些P4功能都是独立的。
And you can add them without impacting the rest of the switch, right, so.
并且你可以在不影响交换机其余部分的情况下添加它们，对吧，所以。
So we want to design this kind of new P4 target architecture that
所以我们想设计这种新的P4目标架构，它
allows us to run multiple small, lightweight P4 programs,
允许我们运行多个小型、轻量级的P4程序，
which we call P4 functions to run them in isolation and
使它们在隔离环境中运行，并使它们具有独立的状态。
to have them have a separate state.
让它们具有独立的状态。
So we can have every default function be reconfigurable separately
因此，我们可以让每个默认功能都可以单独重新配置。
without impacting anything else, so without causing any down side.
因此，不会影响其他任何事物，也不会造成任何负面影响。
And also because the main context of our work is the NDN protocol,
并且因为我们工作的主要背景是NDN协议，
we want to extend the P4 language in efficient way in order to
我们希望以高效的方式扩展P4语言，以便
allow all these string processing operations that are critical for
允许所有这些对于支持NDN协议至关重要的字符串处理操作。
the support of the NDN protocol.
支持NDN协议。
While at the same time being compatible with the P4
同时兼容P4
language standard so we can use the normal P4 compilers without any modification.
语言标准，因此我们可以使用普通的P4编译器而无需任何修改。
Next slide, please.
下一张幻灯片，请。
So this is an outline of the data plane architecture that we propose.
所以这是我们提出的数据平面架构的概要。
So the main goal of this architecture is, as I said, to be able to assign
所以这个架构的主要目标，正如我所说的，是能够分配
the complex stateful forwarding behavior to a specific namespace,
将复杂的有状态转发行为分配到一个特定的命名空间中，
for example, to do things like telemetering,
例如，进行遥测这样的事情，
geo-monitoring, geo-fencing, stateful firewall etc.
地理监控、地理围栏、有状态防火墙等。
And so our architecture has two main modules.
因此，我们的架构有两个主要模块。
The first module is called the EProcessing module, which I will say basically
第一个模块称为EProcessing模块，基本上我会说它包含主要的NDN转发管道以及一些修改。
contains the main NDN forwarding pipeline with some modifications
包含主要的NDN转发管道以及一些修改。
in order to do this assignment of a P4 function to a namespace.
为了将P4功能分配给一个命名空间。
And once this EProcessing finishes with the processing of packets,
一旦这个EProcessing完成了数据包的处理，
therefore added to the new module which is called Forwarding Logic,
因此添加到了一个称为转发逻辑的新模块中，
which contains a set of different P4 functions running in isolations
因此被添加到了一个包含一系列在隔离环境中运行的不同P4功能的新模块中，
that will process these NDN packets in order to
因此将处理这些NDN数据包以便
do any type of forwarding behaviors that the network operates or wants to do.
进行任何类型的转发行为，这是网络运作或希望执行的操作。
And then these packets are passed towards the Parser that may
然后这些数据包被传递到解析器，解析器可能会
optionally modify the packets based on instructions from the P4 function before
在此之前，根据P4功能的指令，可以选择性地修改数据包。
the packets are forwarded through the faces and go to to the next host.
数据包通过接口被转发，并发送到下一个主机。
We did also small modifications where we put the content store outside of the fast
我们还进行了一些小修改，将内容存储移到了快速处理路径之外。
path of the packets in the NDN pipeline.
数据包在NDN管道中的路径。
So the content store is accessed through an internal face.
因此，内容存储是通过一个内部接口访问的。
So the caching decisions can be controlled by adding
因此，可以通过添加控制缓存决策。
a next hop to the CS by namespace so
通过命名空间向内容存储的下一跳添加，所以
the p4 function can control the caching decisions by adding or
通过P4功能可以控制缓存决策，通过添加或
removing this next hop to the content store internal face.
移除到内容存储内部界面的下一跳。
And so in the poster session, I'll explain you in more details
在海报展示环节，我将向你详细解释。
what is inside these different modules and how we did this
我们是如何做到的以及这些不同模块内部包含了什么内容。
data plane and how we interface efficiently with people.
数据平面以及我们如何高效地与人交互。
And thank you everyone and I'll see you during my poster session.
谢谢大家，我们海报展示环节见。
>> All right, thank you, Ouassim.
>> 好的，谢谢你，Ouassim。